SUAD ABDINASIR LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM

Mobile: +44 (0)7908535857 Email: abdinasirsuad@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a driven and enthusiastic person with experience overseeing the creative advertising needs across a range of clients. I thoroughly enjoy getting clients excited about creative routes and my strong client relationships creates an environment where the best work can flourish. I have a great understanding of the commercial realities of the business the client is in and can spot opportunities to develop the company's role. This also allows me to help raise the client's creative ambitions whilst providing an excellent service, which in turn ensures client growth and retention.

EDUCATION

Sept 2011 – July 2014 English BA

University of Northampton

Sept 2009 – Jun 2011 A Level: English Literature, Media Studies, Business Studies &

Law

Leyton Sixth Form College

Sept 2003 – Jun 2008 GCSE: including English, Maths & Science

Walthamstow Academy

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Oct 2022 – Present Senior Account Manger - Acting Account Director, AMV BBDO

Accounts: Macmillan, Rexona, Qatar Tourism, Curry's, Young V&A & Lays.

- Across my accounts, I build strong relationships with my clients through the day-to-day
 client relationship which allows me to better understand their business & objectives. As
 well as articulating strategies & briefs to clients & internal teams whilst telling the brand
 story in a compelling fashion and facilitate in the creation of great strategic insight.
- I have a passion for driving business growth and support my Managing Partners & Head
 of Department with identifying ways to make projects more profitable and unlock revenue
 opportunities for the agency.
- I also manage two direct reports and have created a collaborative & nurturing environment for our team to develop within the business.
- I support the wider team in the day-to-day delivery of projects and play a pivotal role in overseeing the production (TV and integrated campaigns across all channels and formats) and ensuring quality of our project deliverables.
- I drive the creative ambition of my campaigns with my clients from the outset of projects. I
 enable the best possible realisation of the idea through ensures work is executed
 according to requirements of the brand. I can forward plan and anticipate potential
 problems / opportunities on projects and know how to resolve issues & adapts plans
 smoothly.
- I have helped the agency excel internally through leading and implementing a way of working process within the department. My strong relationship across departments is how I was able to collaborate with them and enable them to use and adapt the processes accordingly.
- I lead the team's relationship with the finance dept & interrogate estimates & payments to
 ensure tight cost control across all billing, ultimately ensuring good cashflow. I have a
 great understanding & awareness of the big picture of finance (income, profit, scope &
 contract).

- Day-to-day account management across Mars, Esso and GOSH, including full client liaison, budgetary responsibilities, internal and external briefings, and internal team management.
- I work with two Account Executives and an Account Manager where I lead the team with
 the daily account work as well as reporting into my Senior Account Director. I have
 created a supportive environment for my direct reports, troubleshooting when they are
 unable to resolve issues, and mentoring them. I also actively encourage new ways of
 working within our team as these changes have the potential to make the account run
 smoother in our days.
- I have strategic input into both accounts through new business development as well as being involved in the pitch process for new business opportunities. Always keeping up to date with what's best in class and innovatory across all disciplines and have experience of full marketing mix across accounts including TV, Print, Digital, PR, OOH and Social.
- I'm always pushing to get the best work out and ensuring briefs are clear and manage timings from the client and challenging appropriately where necessary.
- Most importantly, leading conversations and negotiations with clients where they relate to project costs.

Aug 2018 - Aug 2021

Account Manager, Havas

- Leading bespoke projects through the delivery lifecycle for Havas' largest clients; BP, Ministry of Justice, Pfizer, Maersk, Benefit, Next. Being at the sharp end of client contact and developing close relationships and a sense of partnership with clients and fostering trust.
- Managing projects through their lifecycle which includes campaign planning and contributing to the company's profitability as well as always thinking ahead through spotting potential hurdles before they occur whilst managing client and internal expectations and contingency planning as I go.
- Being fluent in the strategic debates regarding my brands and working closely with the planner. As well as working with teams across creative, social, digital, planning, resourcing, and production to ensure work is delivered on budget and to deadline.
- Presenting to clients and key external agency stakeholders for projects as well as supporting client proposals and pitches. Lastly, managing service reviews with the client's senior stakeholders to monitor overall account's performance as well as financial management and oversight of projects.

Jan 2017 - June 2018

Account Executive, Passion Digital

- Account Executive across various ATL and BTL accounts aimed at delivering highperforming digital campaigns.
- Managing projects and having a wide knowledge and understanding of communications collateral to identify the most appropriate channels for clients. As well as identifying opportunities to develop the breadth and depth of services the agency offers and contribute these ideas to form client development plans.
- Working with clients and internal resource to ensure projects were delivered on time and to budget. Alongside, making sure that all work in progress and potential income was reported on a weekly basis so that financial forecasts could be as accurate as possible.

- Working in the client team at Posterscope, world's leading OOH communications agency and location expert. Participated in team meetings, brainstormed ideas for new campaigns as well as helping with existing ones.
- Collating content from across the business to develop quarterly newsletters for alumni and drafting weekly content for use in all Posterscope's internal communication channels. As well as compiling data on consumer patterns and trends and pulling together reports for upcoming campaigns and researched potential partnerships.
- I learnt the importance of maintaining an online presence through digital marketing and developed commercial awareness and learnt the need to adapt to changing demands.

Oct 2015 - Nov 2015

Work Experience Placement, Havas

• A whistle-stop tour of a global agency opened my eyes to the world of advertising. My month involved preparing and presenting competitor analysis for clients, creative brainstorming, research, spreadsheets, and supporting across various departments.